{
  "content": [
    {
      "question": "The first woman president of India",
      "answer": "Smt. Pratibha Patil"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first lady to become Miss World",
      "answer": "Rita Faria"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman judge in Supreme Court",
      "answer": "Mrs. Meera Sahib Fatima Bibi"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman Ambassador",
      "answer": "Miss C.B. Muthamma"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman Governor of a State in free India",
      "answer": "Mrs. Sarojini Naidu"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman Prime Minister",
      "answer": "Mrs. Indira Gandhi"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman to climb Mount Everest",
      "answer": "Bachhendri Pal"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman to climb Mount Everest twice",
      "answer": "Santosh Yadav"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman President of the Indian National Congress",
      "answer": "Mrs. Annie Besant"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman chief justice of a High Court",
      "answer": "Mrs. Leela Seth"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman pilot in Indian Air Force",
      "answer": "Harita Kaur Dayal"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman President of the United Nations General Assembly",
      "answer": "Mrs. Vijaya Laxmi Pandit"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman Chief Minister of an Indian State",
      "answer": "Mrs. Sucheta Kripalani"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman chairman of Union Public Service Commission",
      "answer": "Roze Millian Bethew"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman Director General of Police (DGP)",
      "answer": "Kanchan Chaudhary Bhattacharya"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman Lieutenent General",
      "answer": "Puneeta Arora"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman Air Vice Marshal",
      "answer": "P. Bandopadhyaya"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman chairperson of Indian Airlines",
      "answer": "Sushma Chawla"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman I.P.S. Officer",
      "answer": "Mrs. Kiran Bedi"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first and the last Muslim woman ruler of Delhi",
      "answer": "Razia Sultan"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman to receive Ashoka Chakra",
      "answer": "Nirja Bhanot"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman to cross English Channel",
      "answer": "Aarti Saha"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman to receive Nobel Prize",
      "answer": "Mother Teresa"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman to receive Bharat Ratna",
      "answer": "Mrs. Indira Gandhi"
    },
    {
      "question": "The First woman to get Ashok Chakra",
      "answer": "Nirja Mishra"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first woman to receive Jnanpith Award",
      "answer": "Ashapurna Devi"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Indian woman to swim across the English Channel",
      "answer": "Miss Arati Saha"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Indian woman to win WTA Title",
      "answer": "Sania Mirza"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Indian woman Airline Pilot",
      "answer": "Durga Banerjee"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Indian woman to win a Gold Medal in Asian Games",
      "answer": "Kamaljeet Sandhu"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Indian woman to win the Booker Prize",
      "answer": "Arundhati Roy"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Indian woman to go into space",
      "answer": "Kalpana Chawla"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Indian Woman Minister of Indian Railways",
      "answer": "Mamata Banerjee"
    },
    {
      "question": "First woman in the Indian Army to receive the coveted â€˜Sword of Honour' prize",
      "answer": "Divya Ajith Kumar"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Indian woman to fly fighter aircraft solo",
      "answer": "Avani Chaturvedi"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Indian woman to reach South Pole",
      "answer": "Reena Kausal Dharmshaktu"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Indian Woman to become judge of Supreme Court",
      "answer": "Fathima Beevi"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Indian Woman to become judge of Hight Court",
      "answer": "Anna Chandy"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Woman speaker of Lok Sabha",
      "answer": "Meira Kumar"
    },
    {
      "question": "First Woman to beacome IAS officer",
      "answer": "Isha Basant Joshi"
    }
  ]
}
